Guide to the Benjamin and Muriel Goldring Papers and Photographs TAM.374
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Benjamin and Muriel Goldring Papers and Photographs
1900-2007
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Goldring, Benjamin
Goldring, Muriel Goodman.
Pope, Lillian
TAM.374
19.25 Linear Feet in 18 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, and 4 oversized folders.
Benjamin (Ben) Goldring and Muriel Goodman Goldring were lifelong political activists. Benjamin Goldring, a lawyer by profession, served in the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War, and later in the Pacific Theater during World War II. Both Muriel and Ben Goldring were active in the committees organized to fight the conviction and execution of the Rosenbergs and the imprisonment of Morton Sobell. As a specialist in civil liberties law, Ben Goldring gave his time and expertise to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) in its legal battle against the Subversive Activities Control Board from the 1950s to the 1970s; he was also a actiove member of the National Lawyers Guild. In addition to her work with the Rosenberg and Sobell Committees, Muriel Goldring became involved in a wide range of local and national political causes. The Goldrings closely followed national political developments in many areas, from the peace movement to immigrants' and prisoners' rights, and were also community activists in Brooklyn, where they lived. This collection consists of the Goldrings' personal papers, materials related to Benjamin Goldring's service in the Spanish Civil War, background files on his legal practice and his writings on the law and legal history, files on the Goldrings' activities with the Rosenberg and Sobell defense committees, political reference files on their many political and cultural interests, as well as photographs of their families and friends extending from the late nineteenth century through the early 2000s, and a small amount of audio materials, ephemera, and artifacts.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of Series VII (Estate-Related Material). Repository permission is required for access to Series VII. Please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, 212-998-2630.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Lillian Pope on behalf of Muriel Goldring in 2007; additional materials were sent by Pope in 2010. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2001.025, 2001.037, and NPA.2008.001.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 10 series, as follows:
Series I. Personal Material
Series II. Spanish Civil War
Series III. Legal Practice and Legal Research
Series IV. Rosenberg and Sobell Cases
Series V. Political Reference Files
Series VI. Oversize Materials
Series VII. Restricted Material
Series VIII. Photographs
Series IX. Audio Materials
Series X. Ephemera and Artifacts
All series are arranged alphabetically by folder title, with the exception of Series VIII (Photographs), which is arranged mainly in chronological order, followed by folders arranged in alphabetical order.
Historical/Biographical Note
Benjamin (Ben) Goldring and Muriel Goodman Goldring were lifelong political activists. Ben Goldring, a lawyer by profession, served in the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War, and later in the Pacific Theater during World War II. Both Goldrings were active in the committees organized to fight the conviction and execution of the Rosenbergs and the imprisonment of Morton Sobell. As a specialist in civil liberties law, Ben Goldring gave his time and expertise to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) in their legal battle against the Subversive Activities Control Board (SACB) from the 1950s to the 1970s; he was also a active member of the National Lawyers Guild. In addition to her work with the Rosenberg and Sobell Committees, Muriel Goldring became involved in a wide range of local and national political causes. The Goldrings closely followed national political developments in many areas, from the peace movement to immigrants' and prisoners' rights, and were also community activists in Brooklyn, where they lived.
Benjamin Goldring was born in 1912 and died in 2000. He was educated at Erasmus Hall High School and Brooklyn College. He graduated from Columbia Law School and passed the New York State Bar in 1934. A veteran of the Spanish Civil War, he fought on the Republican side as a member of the Abraham Lincoln Battalion from 1937-1938. Arriving in Spain on March 17, 1937, he first saw action at Villaneuva de la Canada and Brunete and was wounded five times, two of which required hospital stays. He was a member of the National Guard of New York State (1936-1937) and then of the United States Army (1940-1941), re-enlisting in 1942 after the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, and serving in the Pacific Theater until his honorable discharge in 1945. He was active in the Civil Rights Congress, and the National Lawyers Guild (NLG). Remaining active in social and political organizations, Ben Goldring wrote many articles and tracts concerning the law and its application. He also wrote in defense of the publication of a minority report on Israeli treatment of Palestinian prisoners as a counter point to the majority paper published by the NLG after a trip to Israel in 1977.
Among his notable legal activities were: assisting Carol King Esq. with the William Schneiderman case, researching the possible transfer of Morton Sobell from Alcatraz federal prison, and representing a fellow Lincoln Brigade veteran before the Subversive Activities Control Board (SACB). He was gratified when, in the 1970s, the Lincoln Veterans finally won their long legal battle to remove the "subversive" stigma from their organization. Benjamin Goldring was also instrumental in obtaining the release of Lencio Pena (a decorated American soldier and Spanish citizen), imprisoned in Spain for anti-Franco activity. In 1982 he secured copies of the testimony of Lincoln Brigade veterans before the SACB and deposited them in the Lincoln Brigade's archives, with his own notes on the case.
Muriel Goodman Goldring (1918-2007) was born, raised, and educated in Brooklyn, NY. She attended Erasmus Hall High School and took classes at Cornell University, City College of New York, and Brooklyn College. She worked at various times as an accountant and as a high school teacher, and was involved in amateur theater and traditional British folk dancing. She was a leading member of the National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case and the Committee to Free Morton Sobell, turning her hand to publicity, letter-writing, and the organizing of public events. These committees agitated first for a stay of execution for the Rosenbergs, and later for their vindication and for the release of Morton Sobell from prison. She became very close to Sobell's wife Helen.
The Goldrings were married in 1951, and stayed connected with their family and friends through extensive correspondence. They shared a passion for social causes and were aware of and or active in many liberal and radical organizations; they also shared a keen interest in cultural pursuits and foreign travel.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Benjamin Goldring Vertical File in the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Vertical Files: Individuals (ALBA VF 2)
Subversive Activities Control Board Records (ALBA 002)
Helen Sobell Typescript "Double Exposure" (TAM 390)
National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case Records (TAM 174)
Scope and Content note
The collection consists of the Goldrings' personal papers, materials related to Ben Goldring's service in the Spanish Civil War, background files on his legal practice and his writings on the law and legal history, files on Ben and Muriel Goldring's activities with the Rosenberg and Sobell committees, political reference files on their many political and cultural interests, as well as photographs of their families and friends spanning the late nineteenth century through the early 2000s, and a small amount of audio materials, ephemera, and artifacts.
Box-Level Table of Contents:
1. Political/general and legal issues (including SACB); 2. Political/general and early labor material; 3. Political/general (including subject files); 4-5. Political/general; 6. Political/general (includes files on CPUSA); 7. Political/general (includes Geneva Convention research); 8-9. Political/general; 10. Political/general (includes National Lawyers Guild and Israel/Palestine); 11. Political/general (mostly NLG and Israel/Palestine); 12. Political/general (subject files, etc); 13. Rosenbergs/Sobell (includes drafts of book chapters); 14. Rosenbergs / Sobell; 15. Rosenbergs / Sobell; 16. Rosenbergs / Sobell; 17-21. Rosenbergs/Sobell; 22. Rosenbergs/Sobell (includes FOIA); 23-24. Rosenbergs/Sobell; 25. Rosenbergs/Sobell (and BG finances); 26. Rosenbergs / Sobell; 27. Rosenbergs/Sobell (and Browder case); 28. Rosenbergs/Sobell; 29. Legal (includes 1950s cases, FOIA, and Rosenbergs / Sobell); 30. Legal; 31. Legal (includes some Rosenbergs); 32. Legal (history and research); 33. Legal (writing, 1950s); 34. Notes and Xeroxes on Medieval English Law; 35-37. VALB/Spanish Civil War; 38-42. Personal/family; 43. Rosenbergs/Sobell; 44. VALB/Spanish Civil War/SACB; 45-51. Rosenbergs/Sobell; 52. SACB; 53-58. Rosenbergs/Sobell; 59. VALB (includes BG's original Spanish Civil War documents); 60. SACB/VALB; 61-62. Personal/family; 63. Legal; 64. Political/general (includes Rosenbergs/Sobell); 65. Political/general and Legal (including SACB); 66. Non-print (almost all photos).
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Negatives (photographic); Law |x History.; Reprints.; Press releases.; Research notes.; Legal research.; Legal documents.; Radicalism -- United States.; Correspondence.; Black-and-white photographs.; Geneva Convention (1929); Color photographs.; Anti-communist movements -- United States.; Clippings files.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.; Prisoners of war |x Legal status, laws, etc.; Manuscripts for publication.; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953 |x Trials, litigation, etc.; Communism -- United States.; Arab-Israeli conflict.; Espionage, Soviet -- United States.; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953 |x Trials, litigation, etc.; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953; Sobell, Morton; Committee to Free Morton Sobell; National Lawyers Guild; National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Goldring, Muriel Goodman.; Goldring, Benjamin; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953 -- Trials, litigation, etc.; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953 -- Trials, litigation, etc.; Sobell, Helen; United States. Subversive Activities Control Board; Reuben, William A.; Pope, Lillian
- Series I: Personal Material, 1912-2000; 294018
  Scope and Content Note
  This series includes personal correspondence, documents and memorabilia of both Goldrings and a number of members of the Goldring and Goodman families. Personal correspondence includes the couple's cards and notes to each other, Ben Goldring's letters to his family while he was serving in WWII, and Muriel Goldring's incoming letters from friends and relatives, including relatives in Israel starting in 1948.
  - "Abridged Prayer Book for Jews in the Army and Navy of the United States", 1917; 294023 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address Book (three), undated; 294024 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Autograph Books (BG) (2), 1925; 294025 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical: BG, Education, 1912 - 1934; 294026 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical: BG, General, 1934-1994; 294027 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biographical: BG, Health, 1981-2000; 294028 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Biographical: BG, Memorial, 2000; 294029 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Biographical: BG, Memorial Guest Book, 2000; 294030 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Biographical: BG, Service Record, World War II, 1940-1945; 294031 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biographical: Family (BG and MG) (I), undated, 1916-1965; 294032 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Biographical: Family (BG and MG) (II), undated, 1916-1965; 294033 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biographical: MG, Education, 1918-1941; 294034 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biographical: MG, Employment, undated, 1941-1968; 294035 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Biographical: MG, General, 1943-1996; 294036 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Home Remodel (BG and MG), 1953; 305890 (Box 1, Folder 14A)
  - Clubs and Organizations (MG), 1931-1952; 294037 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Columbia Law School Alumni (BG), 1976-1984; 305891 (Box 1, Folder 15A)
  - Cornell University (MG), 1946; 294038 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Bertha and Louis Teitelbaum, 1951-1969; 294039 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Bertha and Louis Teitelbaum, 1969 - 1973; 294040 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Between BG and MG, 1950s - 1970s; 294041 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: David Beaver, 1937 - 1940; 294042 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: From BG, 1951- 1990; 294043 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: From BG, World War II, undated, 1942-1943; 294044 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: From BG, World War II, 1943-1945; 294045 (Box 2, Folder 1a)
  - Correspondence: From Israel, undated, 1956-1977; 294046 (Box 2, Folder 1b)
  - Correspondence: From Israel, 1977-1996; 294047 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: From Israel, Cards, 1950-1978; 294048 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: From Israel, Cards, 1979-1986; 294049 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: From MG, undated, 1946-1988; 294050 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, Anniversary and Valentines, undated; 294051 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, Announcements (I), undated; 294052 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, Announcements (II), undated; 294053 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, For BG, undated; 294054 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, For MG (I), undated; 294055 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, For MG (II), Undated; 294056 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, General, undated; 294057 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, To Family (BG and MG), undated; 294058 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, Holiday and New Years, Undated; 294059 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Greeting Cards, Thank You's, undated; 294120 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: John Howard Lawson and Edward Barsky, To MG, Jun 6, 1930; 344718 (Box 3, Folder 1a)
  - Correspondence: Lency (Mark) Watterud, undated, 194? - 1964; 294121 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Michael Alexander (I), 1943-1944; 294122 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Michael Alexander (II), 1943-1944; 294123 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, 1937-1959; 294124 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, 1960-1967; 294125 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, 1968-1979; 294126 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, 1980-1985; 294127 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, undated, 1986-2006; 294128 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, International, 1957-1998; 294129 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Richard (Dick) Cohn, 1944-1945; 294130 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Richard (Dick) Leonard, 1953-1985; 294131 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Ruth and Morris E. L. Shapiro, 1958-1979; 294132 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Ruth and Morris E. L. Shapiro, 1979-1985; 294133 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: To and From Family (BG and MG), undated, 1926-1990; 294134 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: To BG, 1941-1990; 294135 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: To BG and MG, From Family, undated, 1951-1955; 294136 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: To BG and MG, From Family, 1956-1962; 294137 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: To BG and MG, From Family, 1963-1967; 294138 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: To BG and MG, From Family, 1967-1984; 294139 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: To BG and MG, From Family, 1984-1999; 294140 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: To BG and MG, From Friends, undated, 1954-1996; 294143 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: To BG and MG, re: BG Stroke, Undated, 1990; 327878 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: To MG, General, 1938-1990; 294144 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: To MG, From Family, 1944-2003; 294145 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: To MG, From Friends, 1931-1946; 294146 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: To MG, From Friends, 1947-1999; 294147 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: To MG, From Friends, undated; 294148 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Folk Dancing: General, 1964-2001; 294149 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Folk Dancing: Instructions, undated; 294150 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Folk Dancing: Instructions (Books) I, 1957-1978; 294151 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Folk Dancing: Instructions (Books) II, 1957-1978; 294152 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Goodman, Max "Plan for Post War Employment; Outline of Plan for a Cooperative Bookkeeping Service for Small Businesses to be Managed by and for Paraplegics", 1939-1948; 294153 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Graduation; The Windsor School P. S. 154 Brooklyn and College of the City of New York (MG), 1929-1939; 294154 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Graduation; Brooklyn College and Columbia University (BG), 1933-1934; 294155 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Headstone Rubbings (Sadie Goodman, Emily Sigal), 1964, 1965; 294156 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Literary Magazines: "Erasmian" (Erasmus Hall High School) (2) (BG), 1927, 1928; 294157 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Literary Magazines: "Talisman" (Seth Low Junior College) (2) (BG), undated; 294158 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Remembrances: "Irving and Judith Rubin", "Jeanette and Sidney", undated; 294159 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Wedding (BG and MG), 1951; 294160 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Writings: Unidentified, undated; 294161 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Series II: Spanish Civil War, 1937-1995; 294019
  This series consists mostly of correspondence between Ben Goldring and other Abraham Lincoln Brigade veterans, as well as mailings, flyers, programs and other items from VALB. Also included is Ben' Goldring's correspondence from Spain to his family.
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives, Undated, 1989-2001; 326947 (Box 4, Folder 19a)
  - African - American Volunteers, undated, 1978-1980; 294184 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Bethune Memorial House, 1976, 1981; 294185 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: From BG re: Spanish Civil War History (especially related to Orwell), 1969-1983; 327025 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: From BG to Family and Friends (Spanish Civil War letters), undated, 1937-1938; 294188 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: From BG to The Volunteer, 1978-1984; 294189 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: From George Chaiken, 1979-1984; 294187 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: From Joe Doyle, 1992; 294194 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: From John Tisa to BG and MG, 1980; 294215 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: From Thomas Danek, 1940-1945; 294192 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: From Vaughan Love, 1979; 294199 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Richard and Helen Leonard, 1938; 294190 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Spanish Civil War Prisoners of War, 1976, 1980; 294197 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Spanish Political Prisoners, 1959, 1975; 294222 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: To Bella Martin (sister of BG) from Department of State (some via New York Representative Emanuel Celler) re: BG (also includes one letter from the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade), 1937-1938; 327024 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: To BG from Family and Friends, undated, 1937-1938; 294191 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Victor A. Berch (Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives), 1977-1985, 1990; 294186 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Danek, Thomas, undated, 1982-1985; 294193 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Els Joglars (Spanish theater group), undated, 1978; 294195 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - English to Spanish Grammar (published by the International Brigades), c. 1937; 294198 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Harris, Arthur (Abe), 1979-1981; 294196 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War, 1973-1978, 1989; 294219 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Law, Oliver, 1979; 294217 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Lincoln-Washington Battalion: Order to Commander of the Machine Gun Company (copy), Aug 8, 1937; 327244 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Martin, Fredericka: About American Medical Bureau and Women Volunteers, 1977-1991; 294200 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Morgan, Crawford, 1976, 1982; 294201 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1981-1982; 294202 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - O'Toole, Lawrence, 1980-1984; 294203 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Passport Application and Service in Armed Forces of Foreign States, 1966, 1975; 305893 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pena, Leoncio: Certificate of Naturalization, 1946; 294204 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pena, Leoncio: Correspondence (originals), 1959; 294208 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pena, Leoncio: Correspondence (photocopies), 1959; 294207 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Pena, Leoncio: General (originals), undated, 1958-1959; 294205 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pena, Leoncio: General (photocopies), undated, 1958-1959; 294206 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Personal Ephemera from the Spanish Civil War (BG), 1937-1938; 294213 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Picasso, Pablo: Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee Letter, 1951; 294214 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ragner, Albin C., [1940s], 1976-1984; 294216 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Rein, David and Leonard B. Boudin: Work on Behalf of Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1979-1980; 294218 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Ross, Adolph: About VALB Biographical Project, 1984-1985; 294220 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Selby, Vernon, 1981-1982; 294221 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Spanish Civil War Currency (Spanish Republican, German, Soviet), 326948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Spanish Civil War: General, undated, 1965-1996; 327245 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Spanish Civil War Recollections (BG), 1983, 1996; 327243 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Spanish Refugee Aid (letter from Nancy MacDonald), 1960; 294223 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board: BG Article ("Executing Criminal Law through Civil Regulation"), 1964-1965; 296614 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board: BG Article ("Executing Criminal Law through Civil Regulation"), Correspondence and Notes, 1964-1965; 305896 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board: BG Article ("The McCarran Act 'Civil' 'Regulation' of - and only of - Crimes and Criminals and their Instrumentalities to Further Criminal Objectives"), undated; 296616 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board, Correspondence re:, 1952-1954; 294226 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board, Correspondence re:, 1961-1963; 296626 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board, Correspondence re:, 1964-1971; 296627 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board, Correspondence re:, 1980-1985; 327026 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board: General, 1963-1965, Undated; 327027 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board: Notes (I), undated; 294224 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board: Notes (II), undated; 294225 (Box 5, Folder 25)